Ihor Pavlenko

JavaScript developer



First name: lhor

Last name: Pavlenko Date of birth: 11/10/1987 Skype: linkinrain

Address: Ukraine, Mayakovs'koho Ave, 7/169, Kyiv, 02225

Phone number: +380930678937 Email address: ihor@pavlenko.ninja

Profile

I'm a passionate, self-motivated and well-organized professional JavaScript Front-end developer, with 3+ years of experience in solving complex tasks through the writing clean and maintainable code and providing the great user experience that benefits business growth.

Technically:

Have a strong knowledge of vanilla JavaScript and MVC frameworks, such as Sencha ExtJS, and libraries such as Knockout and Backbone.is, as well. My specialization is developing the Single Page Applications (SPA) using REST API.

Personal characteristics:

Open minded and successful working in both team and self-directed work environments. Strong analytical and communication skills, with ability to understand both technical and business requirements.

My rules of development:

- · Clean and maintainable code for colleagues;
- · Friendly experience for the users;
- · Revenues for the business;

My hobby:

Apart from my main work, I enjoying to improving my technical and practical skills and stay updated by developing software prototypes using cutting edge technologies and tools.



Work experience

GlobalLogic Kyiv Ukraine

Javascript web developer / Front-end developer

08/2014 - present

Enhancing and maintaining complex Single Page Application (SPA) based on ExtJS framework as a member of front-end Scrum team.

Achievements:

- Implemented a lazy-loading widget with infinite scrolling using knockout;
- Introduced a knockout.js library for data-binding;
- Implemented new HTML5 drag and drop API;
- Implemented various APIs for third-party developers Integrated application into thirdparty multimedia products using hypermedia REST;

Work experience

GlobalLogic Kyiv Ukraine

Juniour Javascript web developer / Front-end developer

01/2013 - 08/2014

Enhancing and maintaining complex Single Page Application (SPA) based on ExtJS framework as a member of front-end Scrum team.

Achievements:

- Improved customer satisfaction by implementing various customer-specified customizations and providing client-side APIs;
- Migrated to new framework version and styled new version components regarding guidelines.

Education

B. Sc. C	omputer
	science
	Kyiv
	Ukraine

National Technical University of Ukraine «Kyiv Polytechnic Institute»

2012 - 2014

B. Sc. Engineering Kyiv Ukraine National Technical University of Ukraine «Kyiv Polytechnic Institute»

2004 - 2011



Node.js	
---------	--

Languages

English Professional Ukrainian Native Russian Native